<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[jean.arjean]]></title><description><![CDATA[jean.arjean's personal webiste!!! Hooray!]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 01:53:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Habits, Creativity and Art]]></title><description><![CDATA[Habits are really great, they make you move forward when you don’t feel like moving forward. Habits force you to make
progress on your…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-04-04-habits-creativity-art-anthitesis/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-04-04-habits-creativity-art-anthitesis/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Habits are really great, they make you move forward when you don’t feel like moving forward. Habits force you to make
progress on your project. They’re great at that, they do the job, but they’re forced. The big
problems of habits is they make you &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; forced to do something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you feel forced to do something, it feels like a drag, the task also seem much more harder
than it really is. In his article &lt;em&gt;Speed Matters&lt;/em&gt;, James Somers argues that &lt;em&gt;“Part of the activation energy required to start any task comes from the picture you get in your head when you imagine doing it. It may not be that going for a run is actually costly; but if it feels costly, if the picture in your head looks like a slog, then you will need a bigger expenditure of will to lace up.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I believe that tasks we force ourselves to do because
we consider them a daily habit lose their charm. We lose the enjoyment that we can get from doing
something by turning it into a chore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning things I enjoy in daily habits is probably what doesn’t work, I want to be great at programming, so I told myself
that developping the habit of programming every day on side project would be great thing to do. However, now, progrmaming on side projects feels like more work. An
addditional amount of stress I impose on myself.
I want to program  because I feel like it, because I’m excited by the idea of building something great.
Instead I end up programming because I feel like my life depends on it, because if I don’t follow through with my habits my life will have been a waste where my potential was never truly fulfilled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen a lot of comments on internet forums these days (maybe not that many but w/e), about the culture of
enjoyment or the culture of feeling good. How that culture is too wide spread and make for people with misguided priorities, I tend to
agree, seeking enjoyment make us go for the quick fix to our problems and turn us into all kinds of
junkies. Yet, I cannot quite give up on the idea that my purpose in life shouldn’t feel like a chore, it should
be something I truly belive in, something much greater than a feeling of obligation I get from &lt;em&gt;forming daily habits&lt;/em&gt;.
Programming is a creative endeavour, game development probably even more so. Creative endeavours need love,
they need genuine passion, they’re not some fancy daily habits, they’re a product of the human genius. Of devoted passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said in &lt;em&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/em&gt; by James Clear that you should develop habits based on your identity.
&lt;em&gt;“With outcome-based habits, the focus is on what you want to achieve. With identity-based habits, the focus is on who you wish to become.”&lt;/em&gt;
Yet the person I want to become is not someone who is led by mundane imposed one hour a day of side project programming, it’s a person who
programs because he’s passionate about the problem, the solution and the product. I’ll probably end up programming on side projects every day
anyway, but in an enjoyable way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Genius of the Subconscious.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the book &lt;em&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Walter Isaacson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, it is said that people working with Steve Jobs always had to make their
ideas seem like Steve Jobs’ in order for him to like them. I suspect humans have the same relationship with their things imposed on them, when something
feels imposed to them, the &lt;em&gt;imposition&lt;/em&gt; makes them unable to enjoy the moment, all they have in mind is that they’re doing something because they need to,
not because they want to. Daily &lt;strong&gt;Forced&lt;/strong&gt; habitts are probably mostly the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jsomers.net/blog/speed-matters&quot;&gt;http://jsomers.net/blog/speed-matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11084145-steve-jobs&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11084145-steve-jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why I Write]]></title><description><![CDATA[There’s this innate feeling to some people, probably most people, that they’re
not doing enough, they’re not meeting their expectations.
I…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-03-26-Why-I-Write/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-03-26-Why-I-Write/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There’s this innate feeling to some people, probably most people, that they’re
not doing enough, they’re not meeting their expectations.
I have this feeling, some people might call this being ambitious.  That’s actually probably
the word I’m looking for. Ambition makes me feel like I can achieve great things, it also makes me feel like
there’s a lot of weight on my shoulders. The crushing weight of all the things I should
be doing, but I’m not doing or haven’t done yet. Ambition makes me feel like I have a lot of potential
that is not beng lived up to. Potential is a loaded word, as soon as you acknowledge the fact that you have
potential, pressure sets in. You have to live up to this potential or
accept the fact that you won’t meet them and be forever disappointed in yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes me think I have potential is simple, I have a relatively sharp brain, good health,
pretty good work habits, a good upbringing and a lot of free time. I spend a lot of time reading or working
on side projects. I absorb information. I absorb a lot of information,
but I don’t take the time to share it, I don’t
also take the time to fully &lt;em&gt;ingest&lt;/em&gt; the information, which means I might absorb
it but I get no use out of it. I don’t take the time to master it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might have the potential I think I have, but I don’t live up to it, I avoid living up to it, I get interested in many things but I don’t focus. I’ve noticed that while having quite a few interests is very fun,
it dilludes your ability to be truly great at one of them.
I’ve been avoiding focusing too much on anything, &lt;em&gt;keeping my options open&lt;/em&gt;, but also not living up to any expectations I have of myself.
Not deciding to focus on any one thing. Today I’ve decided to take the first
step, I’ve decided that my focus would be programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another note, I’ve also been avoiding sharing the information I absorb because I’m afraid I don’t master it
enough to have a conversation about it. I want to hold myself accountable for what
I choose to learn, and engage myself to master the information I absorb in order to be able to share it afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Focus&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’ve taken the decision to focus on programming for now, or at least for a considerable amount of time, I want
to focus on one thing at a time (this is an idea from Steve Pavlona &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). I figured I’ll be able to get better at things this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- ## A LEVER TO MOVE THE WORLD  I LIKE THIS --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is a strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Richard P. Rumelt, a strategy has three distinct but complementary parts.&lt;br&gt;
This is directly taken from the book &lt;em&gt;Good Strategy, Bad Strategy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;diagnosis&lt;/em&gt; that defines or explains the nature of the challenge.
A good diagnosis simplifies the often overwhelming complexity of reality by
identifying certain aspects of the situation as critical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Guiding Policy&lt;/em&gt; for dealing with the challenge. This is an overall
approach chosen to cope with or overcome the obstacles identified in the diagnosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A set of &lt;em&gt;coherent actions&lt;/em&gt; that are designed to carry out the guiding policy. These are steps
that are coordinated with one another to work together in accomplishing the guiding policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Diagnosis - What is Going On&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m spreading myself thin, I won’t be able to achieve what I want to do if I lack focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t have any serious outlined way of sharing what I do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read a lot, I learn a lot, but I don’t apply or share what I learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Guiding Policy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on one thing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share my progress here to hold myself accountable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coherent Actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a clear focus every week with time set aside especially for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a post a week to keep myself accountable of mastering what I focused on or learned this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Risk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Too much of one thing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now my focus is programming, which is also my job, I might burn out if I spend
all my time doing the same thing without getting rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Risk Mitigation&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good way to mitigate this risk is to make sure I get sufficient rest time even if I spend
time programming outside of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reflections on the Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if the premise of the mentioned book applies well to personal growth, but my current
methods aren’t taking me where I want to, a change of priority is then in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To move in one direction, you must forgo all others. To choose one goal is to forsake other possible goals.&lt;/em&gt; - Mastery, George Leonard &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2008/12/rapid-improvement/&quot;&gt;https://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2008/12/rapid-improvement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11721966-good-strategy-bad-strategy&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11721966-good-strategy-bad-strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/book/Mastery&quot;&gt;https://sivers.org/book/Mastery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lessons learned from building yet another note taking app.]]></title><description><![CDATA[I started building BrainyDump back in October 2018, I needed a chronological note taking application that allowed me to log entries for…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2019-02-19-lessons-brainy-dump/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2019-02-19-lessons-brainy-dump/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I started building BrainyDump back in October 2018, I needed a chronological note taking application that allowed me to log entries for
classes, my personal life (such as keeping tracks of my thoughts) and technical subjects such as programming.
The most important thing about BrainyDump for me was that it had to let me consult journal entries in a chronological way and allow rich syntax. Google Keep almost allowed me to do this, but honestly, Google Keep miss any
type of text styling, which means no header or any type of list. I also thought about evernote, but boy o’ boy is the tagging system in Evernote bad, the UX is off and creating a note for a tag isn’t as frictionless as it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back, creating a custom solution using Markdown files and a git repository probably would’ve worked, but I really wanted to be able to use BrainyDump
on a cellphone. Maybe using Dropbox with different folders per subject and per date would’ve worked, but I really wanted to build a web platform, so
I did. And so BrainyDump was born, kind of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work out what the prototype will be ahead of time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use paper, lots of them, draw, take notes, WRITE EVERYHTING. What are you building, why, what will the main pages of your application look
and feel like. Changing the prototype during development *&lt;em&gt;WILL BE A HUGE WASTE OF TIME&lt;/em&gt;
Know what the final, prototype ready, interface of your software should look like when you build it,
going back and changing what you built is time consuming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Use frameworks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a web app without using a pre-existing web framework in the language of your choice would be considered suicide by most.
Using a javascript framework is also strongly suggested to make developpement as easy as possible. Using a data persistence library such
as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apollographql.com/&quot;&gt;GraphQL&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/emberjs/data&quot;&gt;ember-data&lt;/a&gt; is also probably a good idea.BUT, CSS is hard, USE A CSS LIBRARY AND THANK ME LATER. Doing all of your CSS by hand is a considerable time investmenent and I tried doing so, it was a bad idea, please don’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Choose the right tool for the job.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure using a new technology might be interesting, and you might treat your project as a technical learning
project, but if the new technology you want to use make the whole process a whole lot harder, a better idea
would be to build the project with a technology you know and like and learn the technology in another &lt;em&gt;funsies&lt;/em&gt; project. The lesson here is: “Use the right tool for
the job” which some Antique Era philosopher could’ve told you WAY back, but here I am perpetrating the same sins that have been commited for thousands of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Split big tasks into smaller tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to look at something as a really big thing that will be hard to accomplish, usually there’s multiple steps that lead to accomplishing
&lt;strong&gt;big things TM&lt;/strong&gt;, don’t hesitate to split this &lt;strong&gt;BIG thing&lt;/strong&gt; into multiple &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; things. Fininshing a small task is a morale booster and is more
encouraging than working on something big that never seems to end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Know who you are selling to&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You better have a targeted demographic in mind while building your product.
It’s important to have a clear demographic and potential costumers in mind while building your product,
this way you know what to do next to satisfy their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Going Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so&quot;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; which is a nice little web app that let me create a personal knowledge base and is super nice, I always had trouble
keeping track of everything in my life and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so&quot;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; really helps me keep track myself and my learnings. Notions doesn’t allow in a straight forward
way to create a logbook, but using tables, it is possible to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Most Important Lesson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get started, stop reading yet another blog post about how to build a MVP, how to make money building a micro SaaS,
how to make A HUNDRED GRAND A YEAR TRAVELLING THE WORLD. The most important advice that anyone will give you is to get
started right away, your idea might suck, your execution might be lacking, but you won’t know any of this
if all you do is speculate and keep &lt;em&gt;preparing&lt;/em&gt; yourself. You’re never truly ready for anything, you improvise,
you learn from your mistakes and you get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So right now, go on github, create a new git repo, give it the first name that crosses your mind, setup a framework in the language of your choice,
create a KANBAN board on Trello(or github projects) that specifies what the next steps to finish your MVP are. AND TOMORROW OR TODAY, &lt;strong&gt;GET STARTED&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck, and don’t forget to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and if you ever want to look at what BrainyDump turned into, here it is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rorscharg/brainy_dump&quot;&gt;https://github.com/rorscharg/brainy_dump&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>