<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[RORSCHARG]]></title><description><![CDATA[Rorscharg's personal webiste!!! Hooray!]]></description><link>http://rorscharg.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 17:35:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Lessons learned from building yet another note taking app.]]></title><description><![CDATA[I started building BrainyDump back in October 2018, I needed a chronological note taking application that allowed me to log entries for…]]></description><link>http://rorscharg.com/blog/lessons-brainy-dump/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://rorscharg.com/blog/lessons-brainy-dump/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I started building BrainyDump back in October 2018, I needed a chronological note taking application that allowed me to log entries for
classes, my personal life (such as keeping tracks of my thoughts) and technical subjects such as programming.
The most important thing about BrainyDump for me was that it had to let me consult journal entries in a chronological way and allow rich syntax. Google Keep almost allowed me to do this, but honestly, Google Keep miss any
type of text styling, which means no header or any type of list. I also thought about evernote, but boy o’ boy is the tagging system in Evernote bad, the UX is off and creating a note for a tag isn’t as frictionless as it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back, creating a custom solution using Markdown files and a git repository probably would’ve worked, but I really wanted to be able to use BrainyDump
on a cellphone. Maybe using Dropbox with different folders per subject and per date would’ve worked, but I really wanted to build a web platform, so
I did. And so BrainyDump was born, kind of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work out what the prototype will be ahead of time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use paper, lots of them, draw, take notes, WRITE EVERYHTING. What are you building, why, what will the main pages of your application look
and feel like. Changing the prototype during development *&lt;em&gt;WILL BE A HUGE WASTE OF TIME&lt;/em&gt;
Know what the final, prototype ready, interface of your software should look like when you build it,
going back and changing what you built is time consuming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Use frameworks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a web app without using a pre-existing web framework in the language of your choice would be considered suicide by most.
Using a javascript framework is also strongly suggested to make developpement as easy as possible. Using a data persistence library such
as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apollographql.com/&quot;&gt;GraphQL&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/emberjs/data&quot;&gt;ember-data&lt;/a&gt; is also probably a good idea.BUT, CSS is hard, USE A CSS LIBRARY AND THANK ME LATER. Doing all of your CSS by hand is a considerable time investmenent and I tried doing so, it was a bad idea, please don’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Choose the right tool for the job.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure using a new technology might be interesting, and you might treat your project as a technical learning
project, but if the new technology you want to use make the whole process a whole lot harder, a better idea
would be to build the project with a technology you know and like and learn the technology in another &lt;em&gt;funsies&lt;/em&gt; project. The lesson here is: “Use the right tool for
the job” which some Antique Era philosopher could’ve told you WAY back, but here I am perpetrating the same sins that have been commited for thousands of years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Split big tasks into smaller tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to look at something as a really big thing that will be hard to accomplish, usually there’s multiple steps that lead to accomplishing
&lt;strong&gt;big things TM&lt;/strong&gt;, don’t hesitate to split this &lt;strong&gt;BIG thing&lt;/strong&gt; into multiple &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; things. Fininshing a small task is a morale booster and is more
encouraging than working on something big that never seems to end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Know who you are selling to&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You better have a targeted demographic in mind while building your product.
It’s important to have a clear demographic and potential costumers in mind while building your product,
this way you know what to do next to satisfy their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Going Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so&quot;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; which is a nice little web app that let me create a personal knowledge base and is super nice, I always had trouble
keeping track of everything in my life and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so&quot;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; really helps me keep track myself and my learnings. Notions doesn’t allow in a straight forward
way to create a logbook, but using tables, it is possible to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Most Important Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get started, stop reading yet another blog post about how to build a MVP, how to make money building a micro SaaS,
how to make A HUNDRED GRAND A YEAR TRAVELLING THE WORLD. The most important advice that anyone will give you is to get
started right away, your idea might suck, your execution might be lacking, but you won’t know any of this
if all you do is speculate and keep &lt;em&gt;preparing&lt;/em&gt; yourself. You’re never truly ready for anything, you improvise,
you learn from your mistakes and you get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So right now, go on github, create a new git repo, give it the first name that crosses your mind, setup a framework in the language of your choice,
create a KANBAN board on Trello(or github projects) that specifies what the next steps to finish your MVP are. AND TOMORROW OR TODAY, &lt;strong&gt;GET STARTED&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck, and don’t forget to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and if you ever want to look at what BrainyDump turned into here it is &lt;a href=&quot;http://brainydump.com&quot;&gt;http://brainydump.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stubborn]]></title><description><![CDATA[I was in disgust, I went mad, I rushed to the bathroom, I looked at the mirror, looked at myself,
looked into my eyes, told myself I wouldn…]]></description><link>http://rorscharg.com/blog/stubborn/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://rorscharg.com/blog/stubborn/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I was in disgust, I went mad, I rushed to the bathroom, I looked at the mirror, looked at myself,
looked into my eyes, told myself I wouldn’t become a cog, told myself not to let go of my dreams,
told myself not to let the fact that everyone else gave up on themlves affect me, told myself I’d never become them,
told myself to keep my childish naivety alive, promised myself not to become a stubborn old man just yet.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Burned]]></title><description><![CDATA[I miss the innocence I had when I was a child The confidence that I would succeed at whatever I tried That when it would matter, I’d have no…]]></description><link>http://rorscharg.com/blog/burned/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://rorscharg.com/blog/burned/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I miss the innocence I had when I was a child&lt;br&gt;
The confidence that I would succeed at whatever I tried&lt;br&gt;
That when it would matter,&lt;br&gt;
I’d have no problem giving my best&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now a few failures later,&lt;br&gt;
I’m terribly scared that I won’t live up to the expectations I’ve set upon myself&lt;br&gt;
That I won’t make it,&lt;br&gt;
fall behind,&lt;br&gt;
be forgotten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m stressed,&lt;br&gt;
burned out of working and studying,&lt;br&gt;
of worrying that I’m falling behind when I’m not working,
of not being able to enjoy having nothing to do without work troubling my mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fast]]></title><description><![CDATA[I really wish things would go faster, I want to be motivated, to have a purpose, to end life in exhaustion because I’ve lived too much…]]></description><link>http://rorscharg.com/blog/fast/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://rorscharg.com/blog/fast/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 22:26:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I really wish things would go faster,&lt;br&gt;
I want to be motivated,&lt;br&gt;
to have a purpose,&lt;br&gt;
to end life in exhaustion because I’ve lived too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School is slow, it slowly burns me out,&lt;br&gt;
turns me into a ghoul,&lt;br&gt;
slowly drags me through the mud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really don’t care about money anymore,&lt;br&gt;
What I really want is to be fired up by something&lt;br&gt;
I want mind to be absorbed by something,&lt;br&gt;
lose track of time,&lt;br&gt;
go on endlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to fall for a long time,&lt;br&gt;
Feel the wind striking my face,&lt;br&gt;
Feel the adrenaline of free falling.&lt;br&gt;
Not look back,&lt;br&gt;
Enjoy the moment&lt;br&gt;
forever&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>