<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[jean.arjean]]></title><description><![CDATA[jean.arjean's personal webiste!!! Hooray!]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 02:42:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Free]]></title><description><![CDATA[Whoever must play, cannot play - James Carse, Finite and Infinite Games  Light Yakuza 0 spoilers ahead, nothing major The third chapter of…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-11-freeeee/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-11-freeeee/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Whoever must play, cannot play - James Carse, Finite and Infinite Games &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light Yakuza 0 spoilers ahead, nothing major&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third chapter of Yakuza 0&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is named ‘Gilded Cage’, the chapter begins as a rich entitled man is causing
trouble in a cabaret, the man thinking he can do anything. The man is interrupted by a young mysterious
man with an eyepatch, he is the manager of the cabaret, the manager handles the situation in an elegant way, he
plays with the man untill he gets him to admit his wrongs and pay the tab for everyone in the cabaret
that night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scene provoked a sense of admiration in me, the manager looked so nimble and agile, it seemed nothing
could bind him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the cabaret manager is interrupted by another character and we learn that being the manager of the cabaret is a punishment.
The manager aka the protagonist has not choice but to be the manager of the cabaret, to redeem himself for his past wrongs. The mysterious
eye patch man has to make money through the cabaret in order to repay a debt indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading Finite and Finite Game by James Carse&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; made me realize I was in a sort of gilded cage too, I made
the choice of going to college (I was strongly encouraged by my parents, but the choice was still mine to make),
this lead up to me accumulating a considerable amount of debt, I looked at college as something I had to go through
in order to live a good life afterwards, I was expecting to be free after college, to truly live the life I always
wanted to live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’m out of college and I’m currently employed, I feel a bit freer but not much, I still have to work, I have to pay
my debts, actually I guess I have the choice not to pay them and see what happens, but my mind sees the debts as
an obligation, something I must get rid of. I do feel trapped, in a cage, I work my shift and when it’s over I’m exhausted, it seems all my productive
energy is going towards work and I can’t get out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to live life freely, have enough money to work on what I want to work on, spending money on paying back my debt is what
I have to do right now, but what I actuallly want to do is save my money in order to be able to spend time in the
way I really want to spend it. I love my workplace and the people I work with but as James Carse has said, whoever
must play cannot play, and this is how I feel right now. I have to play and I end up feeling obligated to work,
obligated to perform, it is an obligation not a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet I refuse to see this gilded cage as an end, I refuse to do like I did in college where I saw it as something
I had to go through, something I really wanted to get over with, I don’t want to tell myself: “just pay your debt and life is gonna be
fine after”. I want life to be good now, and that is a choice I can make right now, I can’t always postpone enjoying life to an uncertain future.
I want to enjoy my time now, be nimble and agile although I’m in a sort of cage,
make the most out of it, life is fragile and I have to enjoy sailing when the sea is still calm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To making the most out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/189989.Finite_and_Infinite_Games&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/189989.Finite_and_Infinite_Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/638970/Yakuza_0/&quot;&gt;https://store.steampowered.com/app/638970/Yakuza_0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Carpal Tunnel Syndrome, Running, Caffeine]]></title><description><![CDATA[I recently started developing wrist issues, my livelihood was pretty much on the line, if you spend 8 hours a day writing code, you
can’t…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-06-carpal-tunnel-syndrome-running-caffeine/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-06-carpal-tunnel-syndrome-running-caffeine/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I recently started developing wrist issues, my livelihood was pretty much on the line, if you spend 8 hours a day writing code, you
can’t afford to hurt yourself, you gotta fix your wrist or find another profession. After a life spent on education that ended up with me as a software developer, that wasn’t
really an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started acknowledging I was being negligent of my body, it’s been falling apart for the past year and it’s something
that really shouldn’t happen to a 24 years old. I have a long lasting injury in my shoulder which I haven’t managed to recover from and which
I haven’t taken the right amount of time to fix either. I’ve been negligent towards myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to take actions, I had to give myself a chance, I knew I had to start doing more physical exercices. I took a small detour however
and decided to read &lt;em&gt;What I talk about when I talk about running&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Haruki Murakami&lt;/em&gt; which I ended up enjoying
a lot, it was a calm book by a man with much more life behind him than me, it was interesting to see similar questionings from someone considerably
older. Someone much older who is according to himself living the life he wants to live. I ended up really appreciating his philosophy of life, of running by necessity to keep himself healthy enough to continue
writing, which is what he has decided is life is about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I started running, I run at least 5km almost every day, sometimes pushing for more. Since I’ve recently started running, I take a day or two off when
I need it in order to give my legs a chance to rest and recover. Rest usually makes a huge difference when I start running again, my legs are much more sturdy
and I don’t feel worried of hurting myself at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wake up at 5:30am, I usually run first thing in the morning, I put on my headphones and listen to an audiobook. Some people have told me they cannot even
imagine listening to something while running, for me it feels natural, it allows me to forget I’m running and focus on listening. I also feel
like it might slow down my pace, I feel a lot faster while listening to music, but I’m not running with a competitive mindset, I like pushing myself, but I don’t care about not running the best time I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day I found myself programming for an hour or so after a run, without drinking any coffee.
At that moment, I realized that my previous stance on coffee, which was I need it in order to perform at work was completely wrong. I really didn’t need coffee anymore. I used to drink
coffee all day and felt absolutely terrible when I wasn’t drinking it, coffee also overstimulated me, it made me feel like I needed more stimulation than just working, I’d end up
opening a thousand chrome tabs looking for something that would release a nice dose of dopamine in my head, I didn’t want to live like this anyomre, I wanted to be able to focus on
things genuinely. Going for a run also made me realize that running woke me up naturally and that I could be focused on programming afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I dropped coffee altogheter, it was a huge pain for the first few days, headaches and tiredness were commonplace, but then I started feeling much better. Now that the withdrawal symptoms are gone,
I can do deep work again, and I only need a run in the morning to feel awake. I am no longer dependant to coffee. It’s been three weeks now, I’m very very happy about the decision,
I am much healthier and the decision has already paid off in my opinion, but I’m sure it will be even more important for my health as/if I get older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d say, the truest thing about all this dropping caffeine thing is that I don’t feel much different, if anything it made me deadly bored, unexcited, don’t get me wrong, I don’t regret the decision, it brought me back to reality.
Lack of stimulants have brought me back to a peaceful life, a boring one, one which might be the envy of many, yet being in it feels horrible. Life has lost its lust, it is plain, there is nothing to be excited about.
Getting rid of stimulants made me realize that maybe the life I’m living right now is due for major changes, that right now I am not very very happy, that it is in my power to make it happier and this is actually
something I’m excited about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2195464.What_I_Talk_About_When_I_Talk_About_Running&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2195464.What_I_Talk_About_When_I_Talk_About_Running&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why I Write]]></title><description><![CDATA[There’s this innate feeling to some people, probably most people, that they’re
not doing enough, they’re not meeting their expectations.
I…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-03-26-Why-I-Write/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-03-26-Why-I-Write/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There’s this innate feeling to some people, probably most people, that they’re
not doing enough, they’re not meeting their expectations.
I have this feeling, some people might call this being ambitious.  That’s actually probably
the word I’m looking for. Ambition makes me feel like I can achieve great things, it also makes me feel like
there’s a lot of weight on my shoulders. The crushing weight of all the things I should
be doing, but I’m not doing or haven’t done yet. Ambition makes me feel like I have a lot of potential
that is not beng lived up to. Potential is a loaded word, as soon as you acknowledge the fact that you have
potential, pressure sets in. You have to live up to this potential or
accept the fact that you won’t meet them and be forever disappointed in yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes me think I have potential is simple, I have a relatively sharp brain, good health,
pretty good work habits, a good upbringing and a lot of free time. I spend a lot of time reading or working
on side projects. I absorb information. I absorb a lot of information,
but I don’t take the time to share it, I don’t
either take the time to fully &lt;em&gt;ingest&lt;/em&gt; the information, which means I might absorb
it but I get no use out of it. I don’t take the time to master it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might have the potential I think I have, but I don’t live up to it, I avoid living up to it, I get interested in many things but I don’t focus. I’ve noticed that while having quite a few interests is very fun,
it dilludes your ability to be truly great at one of them.
I’ve been avoiding focusing too much on anything, &lt;em&gt;keeping my options open&lt;/em&gt;, but also not living up to any expectations I have of myself.
Not deciding to focus on any one thing. Today I’ve decided to take the first
step, I’ve decided that my focus would be programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another note, I’ve also been avoiding sharing the information I absorb because I’m afraid I don’t master it
enough to not look dumb when I talk about it. I also want to hold myself accountable for what
I choose to learn, engage myself to master the information I absorb in order to be able to share it afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Focus&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’ve taken the decision to focus on programming for now, or at least for a considerable amount of time, I want
to focus on one thing at a time (this is an idea from Steve Pavlona &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). I figured I’ll be able to get better at things this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- ## A LEVER TO MOVE THE WORLD  I LIKE THIS --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is a strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Richard P. Rumelt, a strategy has three distinct but complementary parts.&lt;br&gt;
This is directly taken from the book &lt;em&gt;Good Strategy, Bad Strategy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A strategy is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;diagnosis&lt;/em&gt; that defines or explains the nature of the challenge.
A good diagnosis simplifies the often overwhelming complexity of reality by
identifying certain aspects of the situation as critical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Guiding Policy&lt;/em&gt; for dealing with the challenge. This is an overall
approach chosen to cope with or overcome the obstacles identified in the diagnosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A set of &lt;em&gt;coherent actions&lt;/em&gt; that are designed to carry out the guiding policy. These are steps
that are coordinated with one another to work together in accomplishing the guiding policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Diagnosis - What is Going On&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m spreading myself thin, I won’t be able to achieve what I want to do if I lack focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t have any serious outlined way of sharing what I do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read a lot, I learn a lot, but I don’t apply or share what I learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Guiding Policy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on one thing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share my progress here to hold myself accountable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coherent Actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a clear focus every week with time set aside especially for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a post a week to keep myself accountable on mastering what I focused on or learned this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Risk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Too much of one thing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now my focus is programming, which is also my job, I might burn out if I spend
all my time doing the same thing without getting rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Risk Mitigation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good way to mitigate this risk is to make sure I get sufficient rest time even if I spend
time programming outside of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reflections on the Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if the premise of the mentioned book applies well to personal growth, but my current
methods aren’t taking me where I want to, a change of focus is then in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To move in one direction, you must forgo all others. To choose one goal is to forsake other possible goals.&lt;/em&gt; - Mastery, George Leonard &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2008/12/rapid-improvement/&quot;&gt;https://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2008/12/rapid-improvement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11721966-good-strategy-bad-strategy&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11721966-good-strategy-bad-strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/book/Mastery&quot;&gt;https://sivers.org/book/Mastery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>