<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[jean.arjean]]></title><description><![CDATA[jean.arjean's personal webiste!!! Hooray!]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:10:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Free]]></title><description><![CDATA[Whoever must play, cannot play - James Carse, Finite and Infinite Games  ** Light Yakuza 0 spoilers ahead, nothing major ** The third…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-11-freeeee/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-11-freeeee/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Whoever must play, cannot play - James Carse, Finite and Infinite Games &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Light Yakuza 0 spoilers ahead, nothing major **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third chapter of Yakuza 0&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is named ‘Gilded Cage’, the chapter starts as a rich japanese man starts causing
trouble in a presitigious cabaret, the man thinking he can do anything, is interrupted by a young mysterious
man with an eyepatch, he is the manager of the cabaret, he handles the situation in an elegant way, he truly
plays with the man untill he gets him to admit his wrongs and to pay the tab of everyone in the cabaret
that night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scene provoked a sense of admiration in me, the protagonist looked so nimble and agile, it seemed nothing
could hold him in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the character is interrupted by another character and we learn that being the manager of the cabaret is a punishment.
The protagonist has to be the manager of the cabaret, to redeem himself for his past wrongs. The mysterious
eye patch man has to make money through the cabaret and pay it to its owner indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading Finite and Finite Game by James Carse&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; has made me realize I was in a sort of gilded cage too, I made
the choice of going to college (I was strongly encouraged by my parents but the choice was still mine to make), this lead up to me accumulating a considerable amount of debt, I looked at college as something I had to go through
in order to live a good life after, I was expecting to be free after college, to truly live the life I always
wanted to live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’m out of college and I’m currently employed, I feel a bit freer but not much, I still have to work, I have to pay
my debts, actually I guess I have the choice not to pay them and see what happens, but my mind sees the debts as
an obligation. I do feel trapped, in a cage, I work my shift and when it’s over I’m exhausted, it seems all my productive
energy is going towards work and I can’t get out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to live life freely, have enough money to work on what I want to work on, spending money on debt is what
I have to do right now, but what I really want to do is save my money in order to be able to spend time in the
way I really want to spend it. I love my workplace and the people I work with but as James Carse has said, whoever
must play cannot play, and this is how I feel right now. I have to play and I end up feeling obligated to work,
obligated to perform, it is an obligation not a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet I refuse to see this gilded cage as an end, I refuse to do like I did in college where I saw it as something
I must go through, something I really wanted to get over with, I don’t want to tell myself, just pay your debt and life is gonna be
fine after, I want life to be good now, and that is a choice I can make right now, I can’t always postpone enjoying life to an uncertain future. I want to enjoy my time now, be nimble although I’m in a sort of cage,
make the most out of it, life is fragile and I have to enjoy sailing when the sea is still calm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To making the most out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/189989.Finite_and_Infinite_Games&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/189989.Finite_and_Infinite_Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/638970/Yakuza_0/&quot;&gt;https://store.steampowered.com/app/638970/Yakuza_0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Carpal Tunnel Syndrome, Running, Caffeine]]></title><description><![CDATA[I had issue with my wrist, my livelihood was pretty much on the line, if you spend 8 hours a day writing code, you
can’t afford to hurt…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-06-carpal-tunnel-syndrome-running-caffeine/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-06-06-carpal-tunnel-syndrome-running-caffeine/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I had issue with my wrist, my livelihood was pretty much on the line, if you spend 8 hours a day writing code, you
can’t afford to hurt yourself, you gotta fix your wrist or find another profession. After a life of education, that wasn’t
really an option, I didn’t want to learn another proffession because I was too stupid to save my wrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started acknowledging I was being negligent of my body, it’s been falling apart for the past year and it’s something
that really shouldn’t happen to a 24 years old. I have a long lasting injury in my shoulder which I haven’t managed to recover from and which
I haven’t taken the right amount of time to fix either. I’ve been negligent of myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took actions actions, I had to give myself a chance, I knew I had to start doing more physical exercices. I took a small detour however
and decided to read &lt;em&gt;What I talk about when I talk about running&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Haruki Murakami&lt;/em&gt; which I ended up enjoying
a lot, it was a calm book by a man with much more life behind him than me, it was interesting to see similar questionings from someone considerably
older. Someone much older who is according to himself living the life he wants to live. I ended up really appreciating his philosophy of life, of running by necessity to keep himself healthy enough to continue
writing which is what he has decided his life is gonna be about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I started running, I run at least 5km almost every day, sometimes pushing for more. Since I’ve recently started running, I take a day or two off when
I need it in order to give my legs a chance to rest and recover. Rest usually makes a huge difference when I start running again, my legs are much more sturdy
and I don’t feel worried of hurting myself at all. (I wrote this before going for a run this morning and finding my legs pretty tired at the begining of the run).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wake up at 5:30am, I usually run first thing in the morning, I put on my headphones and listen to an audiobook. Some people have told me they cannot even
imagine listening to something while running, for me it feels natural, it allows me to forget I’m running and just focus on listening. I also feel
like it might slow down my pace, I feel a lot faster while listening to music, but I’m not running with a competitive mindset, I like pushing myself, but I don’t care about not running the best time I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day I found myself programming for an hour or so after a run, without drinking any coffee.
At that moment, I realized that my previous stance on coffee, which is I need it in order to perform at work was completely wrong. I really don’t need coffee. I used to drink
coffee all day and felt absolutely terrible when I wasn’t drinking it, coffee also overstimulated me, it made me feel like I needed more stimulation than just working, I’d end up
opening a thousand chrome tabs looking for something that would release a nice dose of dopamine in my head, I didn’t want to live like this anyomre, I wanted to be able to focus on
things genuinely. Going for a run also made me realize that running woke me up naturally and that I could be focused on programming afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I dropped coffee altogheter, it was a huge pain for the first few days, headaches and tiredness was common place, but then I started feeling much better. Now that the withdrawal symptoms are gone,
I can do deep work again, and I only need a run in the morning to feel awake. I am no longer dependant to coffee. It’s been three weeks now, I’m very very happy about the decision,
I am much healthier and the decision has already paid off in my opinion, but I’m sure will only be even more crucial as/if I get older.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d say, the truest thing about all this is that I don’t feel much different, if anything it made me deadly bored, unexcited, don’t get me wrong, I don’t regret the decision, it brought me back to reality.
Lack of stimulants have brought me back to a peaceful life, a boring one, one which might be the envy of many, yet being in it feels horrible. Life has lost its lust, it is plain, there is nothing to be excited about.
Getting rid of stimulants make me realize that maybe the life I’m living right now is due for major changes, that right now I am not very very happy, that it is in my power to make it happier and this is actually
something to be excited about. Lack of stimulants is a blessing in disguise, it’s something that makes me question myself and this I am happy about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2195464.What_I_Talk_About_When_I_Talk_About_Running&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2195464.What_I_Talk_About_When_I_Talk_About_Running&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why I Write]]></title><description><![CDATA[There’s this innate feeling to some people, probably most people, that they’re
not doing enough, they’re not meeting their expectations.
I…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-03-26-Why-I-Write/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2020-03-26-Why-I-Write/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;There’s this innate feeling to some people, probably most people, that they’re
not doing enough, they’re not meeting their expectations.
I have this feeling, some people might call this being ambitious.  That’s actually probably
the word I’m looking for. Ambition makes me feel like I can achieve great things, it also makes me feel like
there’s a lot of weight on my shoulders. The crushing weight of all the things I should
be doing, but I’m not doing or haven’t done yet. Ambition makes me feel like I have a lot of potential
that is not beng lived up to. Potential is a loaded word, as soon as you acknowledge the fact that you have
potential, pressure sets in. You have to live up to this potential or
accept the fact that you won’t meet them and be forever disappointed in yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes me think I have potential is simple, I have a relatively sharp brain, good health,
pretty good work habits, a good upbringing and a lot of free time. I spend a lot of time reading or working
on side projects. I absorb information. I absorb a lot of information,
but I don’t take the time to share it, I don’t
also take the time to fully &lt;em&gt;ingest&lt;/em&gt; the information, which means I might absorb
it but I get no use out of it. I don’t take the time to master it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might have the potential I think I have, but I don’t live up to it, I avoid living up to it, I get interested in many things but I don’t focus. I’ve noticed that while having quite a few interests is very fun,
it dilludes your ability to be truly great at one of them.
I’ve been avoiding focusing too much on anything, &lt;em&gt;keeping my options open&lt;/em&gt;, but also not living up to any expectations I have of myself.
Not deciding to focus on any one thing. Today I’ve decided to take the first
step, I’ve decided that my focus would be programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another note, I’ve also been avoiding sharing the information I absorb because I’m afraid I don’t master it
enough to have a conversation about it. I want to hold myself accountable for what
I choose to learn, and engage myself to master the information I absorb in order to be able to share it afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Focus&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’ve taken the decision to focus on programming for now, or at least for a considerable amount of time, I want
to focus on one thing at a time (this is an idea from Steve Pavlona &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). I figured I’ll be able to get better at things this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- ## A LEVER TO MOVE THE WORLD  I LIKE THIS --&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is a strategy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Richard P. Rumelt, a strategy has three distinct but complementary parts.&lt;br&gt;
This is directly taken from the book &lt;em&gt;Good Strategy, Bad Strategy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;diagnosis&lt;/em&gt; that defines or explains the nature of the challenge.
A good diagnosis simplifies the often overwhelming complexity of reality by
identifying certain aspects of the situation as critical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;Guiding Policy&lt;/em&gt; for dealing with the challenge. This is an overall
approach chosen to cope with or overcome the obstacles identified in the diagnosis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A set of &lt;em&gt;coherent actions&lt;/em&gt; that are designed to carry out the guiding policy. These are steps
that are coordinated with one another to work together in accomplishing the guiding policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Diagnosis - What is Going On&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m spreading myself thin, I won’t be able to achieve what I want to do if I lack focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t have any serious outlined way of sharing what I do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read a lot, I learn a lot, but I don’t apply or share what I learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Guiding Policy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on one thing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share my progress here to hold myself accountable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coherent Actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a clear focus every week with time set aside especially for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a post a week to keep myself accountable of mastering what I focused on or learned this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Risk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Too much of one thing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now my focus is programming, which is also my job, I might burn out if I spend
all my time doing the same thing without getting rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Risk Mitigation&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good way to mitigate this risk is to make sure I get sufficient rest time even if I spend
time programming outside of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reflections on the Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if the premise of the mentioned book applies well to personal growth, but my current
methods aren’t taking me where I want to, a change of priority is then in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To move in one direction, you must forgo all others. To choose one goal is to forsake other possible goals.&lt;/em&gt; - Mastery, George Leonard &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2008/12/rapid-improvement/&quot;&gt;https://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2008/12/rapid-improvement/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-2&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11721966-good-strategy-bad-strategy&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11721966-good-strategy-bad-strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/book/Mastery&quot;&gt;https://sivers.org/book/Mastery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-3&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lessons learned from building yet another note taking app.]]></title><description><![CDATA[I started building BrainyDump back in October 2018, I needed a chronological note taking application that allowed me to log entries for…]]></description><link>https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2019-02-19-lessons-brainy-dump/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://jeanarjean.com/blog/2019-02-19-lessons-brainy-dump/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I started building BrainyDump back in October 2018, I needed a chronological note taking application that allowed me to log entries for
classes, my personal life (such as keeping tracks of my thoughts) and technical subjects such as programming.
The most important thing about BrainyDump for me was that it had to let me consult journal entries in a chronological way and allow rich syntax. Google Keep almost allowed me to do this, but honestly, Google Keep miss any
type of text styling, which means no header or any type of list. I also thought about evernote, but boy o’ boy is the tagging system in Evernote bad, the UX is off and creating a note for a tag isn’t as frictionless as it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back, creating a custom solution using Markdown files and a git repository probably would’ve worked, but I really wanted to be able to use BrainyDump
on a cellphone. Maybe using Dropbox with different folders per subject and per date would’ve worked, but I really wanted to build a web platform, so
I did. And so BrainyDump was born, kind of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work out what the prototype will be ahead of time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use paper, lots of them, draw, take notes, WRITE EVERYHTING. What are you building, why, what will the main pages of your application look
and feel like. Changing the prototype during development *&lt;em&gt;WILL BE A HUGE WASTE OF TIME&lt;/em&gt;
Know what the final, prototype ready, interface of your software should look like when you build it,
going back and changing what you built is time consuming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Use frameworks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a web app without using a pre-existing web framework in the language of your choice would be considered suicide by most.
Using a javascript framework is also strongly suggested to make developpement as easy as possible. Using a data persistence library such
as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apollographql.com/&quot;&gt;GraphQL&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/emberjs/data&quot;&gt;ember-data&lt;/a&gt; is also probably a good idea.BUT, CSS is hard, USE A CSS LIBRARY AND THANK ME LATER. Doing all of your CSS by hand is a considerable time investmenent and I tried doing so, it was a bad idea, please don’t do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Choose the right tool for the job.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure using a new technology might be interesting, and you might treat your project as a technical learning
project, but if the new technology you want to use make the whole process a whole lot harder, a better idea
would be to build the project with a technology you know and like and learn the technology in another &lt;em&gt;funsies&lt;/em&gt; project. The lesson here is: “Use the right tool for
the job” which some Antique Era philosopher could’ve told you WAY back, but here I am perpetrating the same sins that have been commited for thousands of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Split big tasks into smaller tasks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to look at something as a really big thing that will be hard to accomplish, usually there’s multiple steps that lead to accomplishing
&lt;strong&gt;big things TM&lt;/strong&gt;, don’t hesitate to split this &lt;strong&gt;BIG thing&lt;/strong&gt; into multiple &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; things. Fininshing a small task is a morale booster and is more
encouraging than working on something big that never seems to end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Know who you are selling to&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You better have a targeted demographic in mind while building your product.
It’s important to have a clear demographic and potential costumers in mind while building your product,
this way you know what to do next to satisfy their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Going Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so&quot;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; which is a nice little web app that let me create a personal knowledge base and is super nice, I always had trouble
keeping track of everything in my life and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so&quot;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; really helps me keep track myself and my learnings. Notions doesn’t allow in a straight forward
way to create a logbook, but using tables, it is possible to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Most Important Lesson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get started, stop reading yet another blog post about how to build a MVP, how to make money building a micro SaaS,
how to make A HUNDRED GRAND A YEAR TRAVELLING THE WORLD. The most important advice that anyone will give you is to get
started right away, your idea might suck, your execution might be lacking, but you won’t know any of this
if all you do is speculate and keep &lt;em&gt;preparing&lt;/em&gt; yourself. You’re never truly ready for anything, you improvise,
you learn from your mistakes and you get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So right now, go on github, create a new git repo, give it the first name that crosses your mind, setup a framework in the language of your choice,
create a KANBAN board on Trello(or github projects) that specifies what the next steps to finish your MVP are. AND TOMORROW OR TODAY, &lt;strong&gt;GET STARTED&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck, and don’t forget to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and if you ever want to look at what BrainyDump turned into, here it is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rorscharg/brainy_dump&quot;&gt;https://github.com/rorscharg/brainy_dump&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>